A Guide to the Rex Warner Papers 1969.0003
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
Rex Warner Papers
1945-1970
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
Warner, Rex, 1905-1986
1969.0003
1.25 Linear Feet
Author, translator and professor of English, Rex Warner was born 9 March 1905, in Birmingham, England, the son of Frederick Ernest (a clergyman) and Kathleen (Luce) Warner. Educated at Wadham College, Oxford (B.A. with honors, 1928), Warner was a member of the British Home Guard from 1942 until 1945. He was the Tallman Professor of Classics at Bowdoin College (1961-1962) before joining the English faculty at the University of Connecticut in 1962. Warner retired from the University after eleven years and died in 1986.
Biography
Author, translator and professor of English, Rex Warner was born 9 March 1905, in Birmingham, England, the son of Frederick Ernest (a clergyman) and Kathleen (Luce) Warner. Educated at Wadham College, Oxford (B.A. with honors, 1928), Warner was a member of the British Home Guard from 1942 until 1945. He was employed as a teacher in England and Egypt (1928-1945) and was associated with the control commission in Berlin, Germany (1945) and director of British Institute in Athens, Greece (1945-1948) before coming to the United States in 1961. He was the Tallman Professor of Classics at Bowdoin College (1961-1962) before joining the English faculty at the University of Connecticut in 1962. Warner was an Honorary fellow of Wadham College, Oxford; awarded the Black Memorial Prize (1961); decorated commander of the Royal Order of the Phoenix (Greece, 1963); and received D. Litt. from Rider College (1968).
Warner retired from the University after eleven years and died in 1986.
Scope and Content
The collection contains manuscripts and typescripts of essays, articles, lectures, translations, reviews, broadcasts and notes pertaining to Warner's interests in Greece and Greek authors. Materials have been arranged by format or implied format: Books, Broadcasts, Essays, Lectures, Reviews and Translations. Manuscripts concerning Thucydides, Sophocles, and Horace> have been included with the information on The Stories of the Greeks for lack of a clear attribution.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by Dr. Warner in several stages beginning in 1970.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Manuscripts (document genre); British literature; Reviews (document genre); United Kingdom (nation); Educators; Twentieth century.; Translators; Notebooks; Television broadcasting; Personal papers; Radio broadcasting; Correspondence; Essays; Fiction; Scripts (documents); Authors; University of Connecticut; British Broadcasting Corporation.
- Series I: Books, undated, 1967
  - The Converts
    - Notebook, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Notebook, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Notebooks, undated (Box 3, Folder 23-24)
  - The Stories of the Greeks
    - Introduction, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Horace, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Sophocles, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Thucycidides, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series II: Broadcasts, undated, 1945-1956
  - "The Appeal of Greece", undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Aspects of Contemporary Greece", 1948 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - "Audacity", 1956 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - "E.M. Forster", undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Spirit of the Age #3—John Milton", 1955 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - "Survey on Liberty", 1950 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - "Talks for Sixth Forms: Euripides and Greek Drama", 1954 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - "What's the point of Poetry?", 1945 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Series III: Essays, undated
  - "The Appeal of Greece", undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Classics and Humanism", undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "E.M. Forster", undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "An Englishman at Bowdoin", undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Myth of Promethius", undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Personal anthology on Greece, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Series IV: Lectures, undated
  - George Seferis, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - "Julius Caesar and the Idea of a Dictator", undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Series V: Reviews, undated, circa 1967
  - Beware of Caesar, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Fire from Heaven, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - The Holy Land in the Time of Jesus, undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Julian, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Realms of Gold, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - The Republic of Plato, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Taken Care Of: The Autobiography of Edith Sitwell, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - No Laughing Matter, circa 1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Series VI: Translations, undated, circa 1970
  - Thucydides' The Great War Between Athens and Sparta, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Seferis' The Greek Style, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Xenophon's Hellenica, undated (Box 1, Folder 14-16)
  - Seferis' On the Greek Style, circa 1970 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Cicero's Selected Essays, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Plutarch's Selected Essays, undated (Box 2, Folder 19-20)